citywire.co.uk 2018-08-27

# Citywire

Citywire Financial Publishers Limited (“Citywire”) is the operator and copyright holder of certain websites ("the sites") including but not limited to citywire.co.uk. For a full list of websites operated by us, please follow this [link](http://citywireselector.com/local). 

Citywire is an independent publisher of financial information and a data provider.

This privacy policy tells you what information we collect, how we do it and what we will do with it and applies when you:

  * Visit our websites
  * Register for our events
  * Are a fund manager who we rate for Citywire Fund Manager Ratings
  * Complete questionnaires or surveys
  * Register for a magazine
  * Have a face-to-face meeting with us

## Visitors to our websites

### Personalisation

When you visit one of our websites we use cookies to record your personalisation settings so the website remembers them next time you visit. No personally identifiable information is stored in these cookies. You can see what cookies are using for personalisation at any time [here](http://citywire.co.uk/money/citywire-cookies/a554695). 

### Third Party Analytics

We sometimes use third party services such as Google Analytics to analyse website user activity. Personally identifiable information is never shared with these services. You can see what cookies are using for personalisation at any time [here](http://citywire.co.uk/money/citywire-cookies/a554695). 

### Your profile

To read some of our content we may ask you to create a Citywire account (your profile). To do this we ask you provide us with your email address (in the case of our professional sites this should be your work email address), and other information prompted on the registration page. We ask that you provide accurate information: we may use publicly available information on the Internet (such as LinkedIn) to verify that your email address is valid, along with other information you provide at the time of registration. The information you provide is stored in our secure databases and is used to create and/or add to your user profile.

**How we use your profile**

When you visit our websites we use a cookie to assign you a randomly generated unique identifier. We log your activity on our websites against this identifier in our databases. Once in our databases, this information will be added to your user profile and we use this data to deliver you content and advertisements that are relevant to you and improve your user experience.

**Sharing Your Profile**

We do not share personally identifiable information with digital and print advertisers. We may share, however, an anonymised version of this information with companies that advertise, or may advertise, on our sites. By allowing companies to advertise on our sites we are able to offer you content for free.

## Consent to receive third party marketing

If you have opted in to receive third party marketing from our selected partners, we may send marketing emails to you on behalf of asset managers and other financial institutions so that they can send you relevant marketing and advertisements. We never pass your details to them directly, but may use trusted third party data processing companies. We ensure that they handle your data securely and delete it from their systems once processed. For more information on our third party data processing companies, please email privacy@citywire.co.uk.

## Emails

When you create an account with us you will be asked if you want to opt in to receive our daily newsletters. You can opt out of this at any time in the ‘My Account’ section of the websites. You can also use this function to choose to subscribe to any of our other more specific news emails that you want to. We may use the information you have provide us with, along with the information we have collected from your website activities, to subscribe you to email newsletters that we feel would be relevant to you. You can opt out of these in the same way as all other newsletters.

If you opt in to receive direct marketing from us we will send you carefully selected emails marketing our events and other products. These will never be excessive or irrelevant to you and you can opt out of receiving them at any time via the ‘My Account’ section of the website or by emailing privacy@citywire.co.uk.

## Events registration

If you sign up to attend one of our events we will ask you to provide your professional details. This is so we can assess your suitability to attend our event, contact you to let you know if you meet our criteria and share with you with all logistical information.

If you register for one of our events we will use this information internally for liaising with you and ensuring that you are added to appropriate workshops and seminars at the event.

If you are coming to one of our events we may ask you for further information such as your dietary requirements, passport details and any special needs or requirements in accordance with the Discrimination Act 2010. This information will be treated with the upmost respect and will only be used for logistical purposes to make sure you have a comfortable and enjoyable experience at our event.

Also, we may pass some of the information we collect at registration to our event sponsors so that they know who will be attending the event and they can contact you after the event for one feedback call or email and to send you one marketing email – after that it is up to you whether you remain in contact with them.

We may share your job title and company name with potential sponsors so they know the calibre of people that attend our events. We will never share any of your personal data with potential sponsors without your explicit consent.

At the events we will ask you to complete surveys via electronic tablets or paper. These may be to gain feedback on our events, some will be about the type of funds or assets you have under management (if relevant). Some may give you a chance to tell us about your organisation and if you think there is anyone else there that would like to attend an event. This information is added to your user profile and aids us in continuing to offer you relevant content and to invite you to future events.

We also sometimes run surveys at our events on behalf of the event sponsors. If this is the case, then we will check that you are happy to share your answers and personal data with a third party, namely the sponsor.

There will be a photographer and/or videographer at our events. This may be used for future event show guides and our websites or social media channels.

## Questionnaires and Surveys

At Citywire we value your opinion and we often run surveys and questionnaires via email or telephone. These are primarily so we can stay engaged with our audience but are sometimes on behalf of third parties. When they are on behalf of third parties we will state that this is the case at the beginning of the survey, and your personal data such as name and email address will not be shared unless you give express permission to do so. Otherwise, all data is anonymised and aggregated, and cannot be attributed to you.

When we conduct the surveys for our own information the answers you give may be aggregated and anonymised and used for both internal and external presentations and news stories. Such information will also be stored in our database and added to your user profile.

## Magazine registration

In order to send you a hard copy of one of our magazines we ask you to provide us with your postal address. This is shared with our printers and couriers services for logistical purposes but we never share it with any other companies for marketing purposes and we will not send you marketing via the post unless you opt in for this option. The address will be added to your user profile in our database and may be used for geographical profiling.

## Face to face meetings

Citywire likes to engage with our audience and will sometimes request the chance to meet you and ask you questions. We will usually record and then transcribe any meeting that we have. Any opinions that you express will be stored in our database and will be linked to your user profile on the condition that you give us your opt in consent to do this.

## Citywire Fund Manager Ratings

Citywire operate a ratings system based on the performance of fund managers. As part of this, if you are an active fund manager, you may be contacted by Citywire staff for your photograph, a short biography, date of birth, career history and any other relevant information. They will ask you if you are happy for us to use and publish this information as part of your manager profile. If you say yes then this information will be added to our database and published online. We will regularly check in with you that this information is up to date and that you are happy with our continued publication of it.

Data transfers Citywire is a global business with offices in London, Munich, Singapore, Milan and New York. Internally we will share your data in the methods described in this policy. We have EU approved Model Contract Clauses in place between all of our entities so you have adequate protection if your data is transferred to a country which has not been assessed by the European Commission as having adequate legal protection.

If you consent to us transferring your data to a third party outside of the approved jurisdiction we will always make sure that we have a contractual agreement in place which obligates the third party to offer the same protection to your data as would be given under the GDPR.

## Our security

We want our users and members to feel confident using our services and are committed to protecting the information that we collect. Information transmitted to us over the internet is secured using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and industry standard firewalls. We ensure information once received is stored securely and only accessible with the correct authorisation.

## Data Protection Officer

Citywire’s data protection officer’s details and credentials are below:

Data Protection Officer  
Citywire Financial Publishers Limited  
87 Vauxhall Walk  
Vauxhall  
SE11 5HJ  
United Kingdom  
+44 207 840 2461  

## Access or deletion of your personal data

If you wish to exercise your ‘Right to Access’ or ‘Right to be Forgotten’ under the General Data Protection Regulation then please get in touch with us at privacy@citywire.co.uk or call +44 207 840 2250. You can also write to us -

Data Protection Officer  
Citywire Financial Publishers Limited  
87 Vauxhall Walk  
Vauxhall  
SE11 5HJ  
United Kingdom
